Finding Aid for the Aron Kuppermann Papers 1946-2012
Caltech Archives
- Talks and Meetings, Series 6.
  - The National Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure (NPACI) meeting, San Diego, California, March 6-8, 2002 (Box 69, Folder 34)
  - "The Bohnian interpretation of quantum reaction dynamics," The Hebrew University, Jerusalem, Israel, April 24-28, 2002 (Box 69, Folder 35)
  - The National Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure (NPACI) Executive Committee meeting, Marina Del Rey, California, May 29-30, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - World Bank Mission to Brazil, June 6-25, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Conference on Dynamics of Molecular Collisions (MOLEC XIV), Istanbul, Turkey, August 31 - September 7, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - The National Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure (NPACI) Executive Committee meeting, Berkeley, California, October 11-15, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - The National Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure (NPACI) meeting, La Jolla, California, March 17-12, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - The National Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure (NPACI) Executive Committee meeting, Madison, Wisconsin, May 29-30, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - "Quantum reaction dynamics and hyperspherical harmonics," Jortnerfest Symposium, Tel Aviv University, Israel, June 15-17, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - "State to state reaction dynamics in tetratomic systems," Workshop on Quantum Reactive Scattering, El Escorial, Spain, June 20-23, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - "Hyperspherical harmonics for triatomic and tetratomic systems," International Conference on Photonic, Electronic and Atomic Collisions (ICPEAC), Stockholm, Sweden, July 23- 29, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - "Multiple potential energy surface quantum reaction dynamics," Workshop on Nonadiabatic Transitions in Quantum Mechanics, Moscow and Chernogolovka, Russia, August 4-7, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - World Bank Mission to Uganda, November 14-22, 2003 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - The National Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure (NPACI) Users Advisory Committee meeting, San Diego, California, April 26-28, 2004 (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - "Symbolic computation in the determination of hyperspherical harmonic in triatomic and tetratomic systems," American Chemical Society meeting, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, August 20-28, 2004 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - "Hyperspherical harmonics in quantum reactive," Computational Chemical Dynamics Conference, Minneapolis, Minnesota, October 6-9, 2004 (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - Institutional evaluation of the University of São Paulo, Brazil, December 2-16, 2004 (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - World Bank Mission to Uganda, March 16-26, 2005 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    Regarding Uganda Millenium Science Initiative Project.
  - "The challenges of computational chemical dynamics," Microsoft Workshop: 'Toward 2020 Science,' Venice, Italy, June 28 - July 3, 2005 (Box 70, Folder 17)
  - "The Hamiltonian of pentaatomic system," Conference on the Dynamics of Molecular Collisions, Pacific Grove, california, July 10-15, 2005 (Box 70, Folder 18)
  - "Incorporating the geometric phase effect in hyperspherical harmonics," Workshop on Quantum Reactive Scattering, University of California, Santa Cruz, July 15-19, 2005 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - American Chemical Society meeting, Washington, D.C., August 27-31, 2005 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - "Accurate reactive scattering calculations using hyperspherical harmonics," Symposium on Atomic and Molecular Chemixstry and Physics, University of Southern California, September 23-24, 2005 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - "Relation between time-dependent and time-independent formalisms of poly-atomic reactive scattering," Dalian Institute of Chemical Physics, China, June 29 - July 13, 2006 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - "Exact quantum theory of chemical reactions and their resources," American Chemical Society meeting, San Francisco, California, September 8-15, 2006 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - "Hamiltonian of a pentaatomic system in row orthonormal (democratic) hyperspherical coordinates," International Workshop on Quantum Reactive Scattering, Cambridge, England, July 4-24, 2007 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - "Pursuing the holy grail of theoretical chemical dynamics," Physical Chemistry seminar, University of California, Davis, November 5-7, 2007 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - "Democratic hyperspherical coordinates for five atoms and beyond," Conference on Computational Molecular Structure and Dynamics, Austin, Texas, January 8-10, 2009 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - External evaluation Panel for Chile's Centers of Excellence, Santiago de Chile, March 8-11, 2009 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - George C. Schatz 60th Birthday Conference, Evanston, Illinois, April 16-19, 2009 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - "Angular momentum operatorsin multidimentional spaces in the theory of reactive scattering of polyatomic systems," International Workshop on Quantum Reactive Scattering, Dalian, China, June 5-10, 2009 (Box 71, Folder 11)
- Research Files, Series 7.
  - Research proposals and grants, Subseries 1.
    - Air Force Office of Scientific Research (AFOSR) 1973-1988
    - AFOSR general correspondence, March 1973- April 1979 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Application for renewal of research grant: "Theories of energy disposal in chemical reactions", March 1974 (Box 72, Folder 2)
      AFOSR-73-2539.
    - Application for renewal of research grant: "Theories of energy disposal in chemical reactions", March 1975 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Revised budget for research project AFOSR-73-2539, 25 April 1975 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Application for renewal of research grant: "The quantum dynamics of chemical reactions", February 1978 (Box 72, Folder 5)
      AFOSR-77-3394.
    - Application for renewal of research grant: "The quantum dynamics of chemical reactions", March 1979 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Final scientific report: "The quantum dynamics of chemical reactions", 14 March 1980 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Final technical report: "The quantum dynamics of chemical reactions", 31 March 1983 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Reference material for inal technical report: "The quantum dynamics of chemical reactions", 31 March 1983 (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Application for a research grant: "The dynamics of simple chemical reactions- theory and experiment", 17 January 1985 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Application for a research grant: "Quantum dynamics of chemical reactions", 30 January 1986 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Request for a research grant: "High energy products from high energy reagents", 29 November 1988 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Air Force Rocket Propulsion Laboratory (AFRPL) 1985-1991
    - Request for AFRPL research grant: "Tetrahydrogen", 13 March 1985 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - AFRPL general correspondence, August 1985-October 1987 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Final technical report: "Tetrahydrogen", 15 October 1986 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Contract FO4611-85-C-0054.
    - Final report: "Tetrahydrogen", January 1987 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      AFRPL TR-86-103.
    - Request for AFRPL research contract: "Theoretical studies of the lifetime of metastable trihydrogen and tetrahydrogen", 29 April 1986 (Box 73, Folder 7)
      Grant FO4611-86-K-0067.
    - AFRPL correspondence (grant FO4611-86-K-0067), April 1986-August 1991 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Technical progress reports (grant FO4611-86-K-0067), 1 August 1986-1July 1989 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Budget status reports (grant FO4611-86-K-0067), March 1987-September 1991 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Final technical report: "Theoretical studies of the lifetime of metastable H3", 30 April 1990 (Box 73, Folder 11)
      Report no. AL-TR-90-039.
    - Request for AFRPL research contract: "Experimental studies of the properties of trihydrogen and tetrahydrogen", 29 April 1986 (Box 73, Folder 12)
      Grant FO4611-86-K-0076.
    - AFRPL correspondence (grant FO4611-86-K-0076), April 1986-March 1991 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Technical progress reports (grant FO4611-86-K-0076), 1 August 1986-1July 1989 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - Budget status reports (grant FO4611-86-K-0076), June 1987-December 1990 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Final technical report: "Experimental studies of the properties of trihydrogen and tetrahydrogen", 28 February 1990 (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - Atomic Energy Commission, United States (USAEC) 1958-1975
    - Final technical report: "Studies in radiation chemistry and chemical kinetics", 15 November 1958-15 December December 1963 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      Contract AT (11-1)-691.
    - Application for a research contract: "Studies in chemical kinetics and radiation chemistry", 31 May 1963 (Box 74, Folder 2)
      AT (04-3)-532.
    - Revision to application for a research contract: "Studies in chemical kinetics and radiation chemistry" (AT (04-3)-532), October 1963 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Technical progress reports (AT (04-3)-532), July 1964 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical kinetics and radiation chemistry", 10 August 1964 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Request for supplemental funds for contract (AT (04-3)-532), 2 October 1964 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Revision to application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical kinetics and radiation chemistry" (AT (04-3)-532), 8 October 1964 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Technical progress reports (AT (04-3)-532), July 1965 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical kinetics and radiation chemistry", September 1965 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Technical progress reports (AT (04-3)-532), 8 August 1966 (Box 74, Folder 10)
      CALT-532-1.
    - Technical progress reports (AT (04-3)-532), 31 August 1967 (Box 74, Folder 11)
      CALT-532-15.
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical dynamics and radiation chemistry", September 1967 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Technical progress report (AT (04-3)-532): Draft, July 1968 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Technical progress report (AT (04-3)-532): Final, 6 September 1968 (Box 75, Folder 3)
      CALT-532-37.
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical dynamics and radiation chemistry", September 1968 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Technical progress report (AT (04-3)-767, PA No. 4, 1 July 1969 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical dynamics and radiation chemistry", September 1969 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Technical progress reports (AT (04-3)-767, PA No. 4, 30 June 1970 (Box 75, Folder 7)
      CALT-767P4-60-63.
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical dynamics and radiation chemistry", September 1970 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical dynamics and radiation chemistry", September 1971 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Technical progress report (AT (04-3)-767, PA No. 4, July 1972 (Box 75, Folder 10)
      CALT-767P4-95.
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical dynamics and radiation chemistry", September 1972 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical dynamics and radiation chemistry", 27 June 1973 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Technical progress report (AT (04-3)-767, PA No. 4, 30 June 1973 (Box 76, Folder 2)
      CALT-767P4-123.
    - Technical progress reports (AT (04-3)-767, PA No. 4, July 1973 (Box 76, Folder 3)
      CALT-767P4-96-123.
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical dynamics and radiation chemistry", 3 July 1974 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Technical progress reports (AT (04-3)-767, PA No. 4, July 1974 (Box 76, Folder 5)
      CALT-767P4-124.
    - Technical progress report (AT (04-3)-767, PA No. 4, 31 July 1975 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Energy, Department of (DOE) 1978-1989
    - Application for renewal of research contract: "Studies in chemical dynamics", 22 November 1978 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Technical progress report: Studies in chemical dynamics" (DE-AT03-76ER72004), 26 November 1979 (Box 77, Folder 2)
      CALT-767P4-183.
    - Technical progress report: "Studies in spectroscopy and chemical dynamics" (DE-AT03-76ER72004), 1 November 1981 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Proposal renewal and related correspondence, October 1983-April 1989 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Request for a renewal of a research contract with the U.S. Department of Energy: "Studies in spectroscopy and chemical dynamics", 15 October 1984 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Technical progress report: "Studies in spectroscopy and chemical dynamics" (DE-AT03-76ER72004), 15 October 1984 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Request for a renewal of a research contract with the U.S. Department of Energy: "Studies in spectroscopy and chemical dynamics", 15 October 1985 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Technical progress report: "Studies in spectroscopy and chemical dynamics" (DE-AT03-76ER72004), 15 October 1985 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Technical progress report: "Studies in spectroscopy and chemical dynamics" (DE-AT03-76ER72004), 15 November 1986 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Proposal: "Electron impact spectroscopy and chemical dynamics of free radicals", 20 November 1986 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Proposal: "Instrumentation for reaction dynamics of combustion processes", December 1986 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF) 1977-2006
    - Application for a research grant: "The study of dynamical resonances in chemical reactions", July 1977 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Revised budget for research grant: "The study of dynamical resonances in chemical reactions", 24 February 1978 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Request for an instrumentation grant: "Intermediate size departmental computer for structural and dynamics studies of chemical processes"(See also: Series 3, Caltech cemistry Ad Hoc Committee on Computing Needs of the Division), 1 August 1978 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Proposal: "Equipment for undergraduate physical chemistry laboratory", 23 February 1979 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Proposal: "An attached array processor for the departmental computer for structural and dynamic studies of chemical processes", 16 April 1982 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Proposal: "State to state reaction cross sections for hydrogen atom abstraction reactions", 18 May 1984 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Proposal to NSF Office of Science and Technology Centers Development: "Center for Scientific Parallel Programing", January 1988 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Proposal correspondence: "Center for Research on Parallel programing (CRPC)", February-December 1989 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Center for Research on Parallel programing (CRPC) budget account reports, March 1989-August 1991 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Proposal: "Electronically non adiabatic effects in state to state reaction dynamics using massively parallel supercomputers" (CHE-9311401), 2 February 1993 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Proposal correspondence: "Electronically non adiabatic effects in state to state reaction dynamics using massively parallel supercomputers", July 1983-May 1995 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Proposal renewal (continuation of CHE-9311401), 1 February 1996 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Proposal renewal and related correspondence, January 1998- December 2000 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Proposal: "Parallel I/O methodologies for I/O intensive grand challenge applications", 15 June 1993 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      A proposal by Paul Messina while Kuppermann was a research associate.
    - Proposal related correspondence, March 1993-December 1997 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Proposal: "Graduate research trainship in high performance computational chemistry and biology", March 1994 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Proposal to NSF Partnership for Advanced Computational Infrastructure Program (NPACI), Solocitation No. NSF 96-31, July 1996-June 2003 (Box 79, Folder 8)
      Proposal submitted by the University of California, san Diego.
    - NPACI proposal renewal, 17 March 1999 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - NPACI proposal renewal, 7 March 2003 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - NPACI proposal renewal, 29 September 2003 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Proposal: "Chemistry Research Instrumentation and Facilities (CRIF)", September 1996 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      Proposal submitted by Caltech Chemistry Division chaiman Peter Dervan.
    - Proposal: "Quantum reaction dynamics of triatomic, tetratomic, and larger polyatomic systems including electronically non adiabatic effects" (CHE-0138091), August 2001 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Proposal renewal: "Quantum reaction dynamics ... including electronically non adiabatic effects" (CHE-0138091), January 2007 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Pre proposal no. 0647490: "Collaborative research, geometric dimension reduction of complex molecular systems", August 2006 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Proposals, Miscellany 1977-1993
    - Beckman Institute proposal: "Calculation of four center reaction cross sections and rate constants", July 1992 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Caltech Consortium in Chemistry and Chemical Engineering proposal: "Reaction dynamics of metastable H3", March 1989 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Caltech Consortium in Chemistry and Chemical Engineering proposal: "Calculation of reaction cross sections and rate constants on the Caltech DELTA parallel supercomputer", April 1991 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Caltech President Fund proposal: "Pulsed ultraviolet laser photoacoustic spectroscopy", January 1979 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Caltech President Fund proposal: "Investigation of a CCD multichannel detector for an electron spectrometer", December 1982 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Camille and Henry Dreyfus Foundation proposal: "An attached array processor for the Dreyfus-NSF Theoretical Chemistry Computer", December 1982 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Army, Army Research Office (ARO) proposal: "Reaction dynamics of metastable states", August 1990 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Department of Defense proposal: "An attached array processor for the Dreyfus-NSF Theoretical Chemistry Computer", November 1982 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - IBM Shared University Research Program proposal: "An IBM RISC system workstation", May 1993 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - U.S.-Israel Binational Science Foundation proposal: "The quantum dynamics of electron transfer chemical reactions", June 1977 (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - Technical Files, Subseries 2.
    - Systems of coordinates for linear A plus B to AB plus C, April 1970 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - An attempt at pre-averaging rotational states, August 1970 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Reactive scattering in three physical dimensions, September 1971 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Reaction on a plane transformation of coordinates I, April-May 1973 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Reaction on a plane transformation of coordinates II, April-May 1973 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Notes on potential energy surface globe, May 1973 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Polar plots, May 1973- January 1974 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Reaction on a plane transformation of coordinates III, June 1973 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Three dimensional reactive scattering I, June 1973 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Three dimensional reactive scattering II, June 1973 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Three dimensional reactive scattering III, June 1973 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Three dimensional reactive scattering by the separate arrangement channel method, January 1974 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Polar plots, October 1974 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Probability current density for 3-D atom diatom reactive scattering I, December 1974- January 1975 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Probability current density for 3-D atom diatom reactive scattering II, December 1974- January 1975 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Quantum theory of molecular reactions, June 1975 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Coupling of electronic and nuclear motion, November 1976 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - De Broglie maps for scattering and bound state problems, July 1977 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - A simple model for dissociative collinear collisions, October 1977 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Systems of coordinates in 6D configuration space appropriate for atom diatom reactive scattering II, October 1977-January 1978 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Systems of coordinates in 6D configuration space appropriate for atom diatom reactive scattering II, October 1977-January 1978 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Considerations about symmetry, April 1978 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Considerations about improvements in 3D reactive scattering calculations, May 1978 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Determination of surface Eigen functions I, September-October 1979 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Notes on integration of systems, October 1979 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Determination of surface Eigen functions II, November-December 1979 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Determination of surface Eigen functions III, Decenber 1979- January 1980 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Determination of surface Eigen functions IIII, February-March 1980 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Determination of surface Eigen functions IV, September 1980 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Invariant imbedding in reactive scattering I, January 1981 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Invariant imbedding in reactive scattering II (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Considerations about the solution of the logarithmic deriative equation without and with a first order term, April-May 1981 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Generalized symmetrized hyperspherical coordinates, June 1981 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Boundary conditions for symmetric Eigen value problems, September 1981 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Symmetry surface functions, December 1981 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Summary of group theory, January-February 1982 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Symmetrized hyperspherical coordinates for N-body systems, June 1982 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Collinear three body recombination I, August-October 1982 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Collinear three body recombination II, October 1982-January 1983 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Collinear three body recombination III, November 1982 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Two electron problems in hyperspherical coordinates, December 1982 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - The asimptotic behavior of surface functions, January 1983 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Relation between symmetry and general matrices, April 1983 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Bound states by scattering methods, April 1983 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Considerations about angular momentum operators and derivation of body-fixwd scattering equations for N-particle systems, April 1983- July 1984 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Local scattering matrices in hyspherical coordinates, May 1983 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - ymmetry considerations about the mapping of the potential energy function of four collinear atoms, May 1983 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Phase space weight in hyperspherical coordinates, February 1984 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Properties of logarithmic derivative matrix, September 1984 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Considerations about uniqueness of scattering and surface functions for triatomic systems, January 1985 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Bound states of particle on a circular slotted wheel potential, February 1985 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Constants of the motion for orthogonal coordinates, March 1985 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - State to state cross sections in electron hydrogene atom scattering, April 1985 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Relation between scattering amplitude and scattering matrix, May 1985 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Considerations about matching wave functions, November 1985 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Possible methods for calculating surface functions in triatomic chemical reactions, January 1986 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Non orthogonality of transformation from space fixed mass scaled cartesian coordinates to body fixed spherical coordinates, June 1986 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Orthogonality of surface functions, December 1986 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - High energy density matter, May 1987 (Box 87, Folder 11)